Guide to the Guerlac-Perrin Lavoisier Archive, 1939-1987.
Guerlac-Perrin Lavoisier Archive
- Series I. Henry Guerlac
  - Materials relating to Lavoisier Archives
    - Photostat Negatives (with original numbering)
      - Journal Polytype, 1786 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Méthod: St. John trause, 1788 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Elements of Chemistry in a New Systematic Order, 1802 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Journal Polytype, 1786 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Kirwan, 1788 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Traité, 1805 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Rapport fait Al'Académie des Sciences sur la Machine Aérostatique, 1784 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Report of Dr. Benjamin Franklin…with the examination of the Animal Magnetism, 1785 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Elements of Chemistry in a New Systematic Order, December 12, 1799 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Elements of Chemistry in a New Systematic Order, 1796 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Traité: "Seconde èdition" Second de Boiste issue, 1793 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Rapport des Commissaires…du L'Examen du Magnétisme Animal, 1784 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Observations et Mémoires sur La Physique, sur L'Histoire Naturelle, et sur les Arts et Métiers, 1781 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Recueil…Salpêtre, 1776 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Rapport des Commissaires…du L'Examen du Magnétisme Animal, 1784 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - 10c, 1p: Exposé des Expériences…du Magnétisme Anima, September 4, 1784 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - A Translation of the Table of Chemical Nomenclature, 1799 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Vocabulary and Tables of the Old and New Nomenclatures, 1796 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Traité: second ed., 1789 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Essai Comparatif de l'Imprimerie ordinaire à l'Imprimerie Polytype (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Etablissement des Nitriéres, 1776 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Traité: "Troisième éd.", 1801 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Opuscules 1st ed., 1774 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Méthode: second printing, 1787 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Annales De Chimie; ou Recueil de Mémoires, 1789 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Traité, 1804 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Traité: "Seconde èdition" Chardon, 1793 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Histoire de L'Académie, 1789 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Opuscules, 1801 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Elements of Chemistry in a New Systematic Order, 1790 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Histoire de L'Académie, 1780 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Instruction sur le Parcage des Bétes à laine (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Oxygen definition (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - Essays Physical and Chemical, 1776 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Traité: nouvelle ed., 1789 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Catalogue de Livres…de feu Madame Lavoisier, 1836 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Grondbeginselen der Scheikunde, 1800 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Méthode 1st ed., 1787 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Traité, 1805 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - Opuscules, 1801 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - Traité: 1st ed. 1st issue, 1789 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - Trattato Elementare di Chimica (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - Footnote on mercure précipité per se, 1775 (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - Histoire (last page of the bibliography) (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Etablissement des Nitrières: reissue An II (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Elements of Chemistry in a New Systematic Order, 1806 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - Journal Polytype, 1786 (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - Gypsum paper (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - Memoires de Mathématique, 1768 (Box 4, Folder 75)
      - Traité: Planche XI (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - Traité: Planche XI (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - Lavoisier illustration (Box 4, Folder 78-100)
      - Observations et Mémoires sur La Physique, sur L'Histoire Naturelle, et sur les Arts (title page), 1785 (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - Lavoisier bust (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - Portrait of Mr. and Mme. Lavoisier (Box 4, Folder 103)
      - Lavoisier illustration (Box 4, Folder 104-106)
      - bookplate (Box 4, Folder 107)
      - signature (Box 4, Folder 108)
      - Lavoisier illustration (Box 4, Folder 109-114)
      - Various Memorials Commemorating Lavoisier (Box 4, Folder 115-123)
      - Mercure de France Dedie au Roi, 1769 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Lavoisier Reprints
    - By Author
      - Loose Manuscripts -- Authors A-De, 1957-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Loose Manuscripts -- Denis Duveen, 1952-1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        Most with Herbert Klickstein
      - Loose Manuscripts -- Authors F-M, 1935, 1950-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Loose Manuscripts -- Siegfried, unlabeled "Revue D'Histoire des Sciences", 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Smeaton, 1957-1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Loose Manuscripts II -- Authors B-K, 1895, 1941-1952 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Loose Manuscripts II -- Authors M-S, 1948-1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        Includes unlabeled "Revue D'Histoire des Sciences"
      - The Svedberg and Molecular Reality by Milton Kerker (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Lavoisier and the Caloric Theory by Robert J. Morris (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - The Chemistry of Salts in the Eighteenth Century by Frederic L. Holmes (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Venel and the Study of Chemisty at Montpellier (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Loose Manuscripts -- Guichard, Homes, Perrin, 1937, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Photocopies/Facsimiles -- McKie & Daumas, Lusk, Mark, undated, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Precursors & Contemporaries
      - Bergman Correspondence, 1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Berthollet, May 1946, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Black, Joseph, 1935-1936, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Boerhaave, H., 1952-1959 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Carra: Examen physique (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Fourcroy, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Guettard (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Guyion de Morveau, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Landriani (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Lewis, William (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Lomonosov, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Macques, P.J. (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Magellus Letters (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Margraff, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Meusnier and assignats (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Joseph Priestley, 1938, 1956, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Letter from (Wedgwood ?) to (Priestley) 2 Sept 1791 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Romé de L'Isle (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Rouelle, G.F. (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Rozier Letters (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Rutterford, Daniel, August 1935 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Scheele, Carl Wilhelm, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Topical Background
      - Enciclopedia di Chimica, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Grant Proposals, 1961, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Manuscripts and Correspondence -- Crosland, 1971, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Traite Élémentaire de Chimie (Box 4, Folder 39)
        Folder with articles and Lavoisier documents
      - Loose Manuscripts - alphabetical by author, 1927, 1943-1963, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Bibliographic Notecards
    - Index to the Ouvres (Name & Subject Index) (Box 3)
    - Secondary Bibliography Part I (Predecessors & contemporaries) (Box 3)
    - Secondary Bibliography Part II (Topical/Subject) (Box 3)
    - Raw material for the Lavoisier Chronology (Box 3)
    - File of 18th c. scientists (Box 7)
    - File of 18th c. scientists (Box 7)
    - File of 18th c. scientists (Box 7)
    - (in box with) File of 18th c. scientists (Box 7)
    - Some raw material for Kardex. (Leslie B.) (Box 7)
    - Raw material for the Lavoisier Chronology (Box 8)
    - Secondary Bibliography - Part III (Box 8)
      Secondary literature on Lavoisier. Arranged chronologically- raw material for MSS BD Lavoisier QD L41 G931+
    - Unlabelled Bibliographic Cards (Box 8)
- Series I. Carl Perrin
  - Microfilm
    - Academie des Sciences Procio-verbaux, 1776-1788 (Box 5, Reel 1)
    - Guyton de Morveau Digressions Académique (Box 5, Reel 2)
    - Fourcroy article: Chimie Encyclopedie Methodique (Box 5, Reel 3)
    - Source: Musée Nationale D'Histoire Naturelle -- "Observations de M. Trebia Sur l'enteueui des montagnes", Schelle's "Traité chimique de l'air et du feu (Box 5, Reel 4)
    - Muséum Nationale diffustoere Naturelle MS 1990-1994 (Box 5, Reel 5)
    - J.B.M. Bucquet "Precis des leçons de chimie de feu M. Bucquet" (Box 5, Reel 6)
    - Genève: Senelrei "Système pour la combustion" Mme Lavoisier Letter to Samsure (Box 5, Reel 7)
    - PS 77 7229: B. Higgins Minutes for the Society…, Nicholson Diet. Of Chem., Opuscoli Scelti Vol.s 14 & 18 (Box 5, Reel 8)
    - PS 77 235: Croustedt (Magellan) "System of Miuer.", Henry (ed.) "Essay on Atom. Air" (Box 5, Reel 9)
    - Monsieur C Perrin: Hotel du Pas. de Calais 59 sur des Saints Peres, Paris (Box 5, Reel 10)
      1260 1st edition d'un cours de Chimie, 93 Opeiscales plup. Et chem. De M. Lavoisier
    - James Keir: A Tretise on the various kinds of permanent elastic fluids on gases, A. Crawford: E. and O. on animal heat, 1779 (Box 5, Reel 11)
    - Envelope of microfilm: Beúhollet "Obs. Sur l'aír" (1776), Bucquet lectures (Box 5)
    - Envelope of microfilm (Box 5)
    - Roll of Microfilm: Guyton de Morveau "Defense de la volatilité du phlogistique…" (Box 5)
  - Computer Disks and Punch Cards
    - Computer Disks
      - Unlabelled disks, 4" Floppy FD-63-64 (Box 5)
      - lavmsst.ask, 4" Floppy FD-65 (Box 5)
        Lavoisier Manuscripts using "ask" a database management system
      - more lamsst.ask, 4" Floppy FD-66 (Box 5)
      - Program Disk and duplicate files, 4" Floppy FD-67 (Box 5)
      - askSam (Seaside Software) user manual (Box 5)
    - Punch Cards
      - Lavoisier Documents Files: Drawer #1, Bundle #1 of 4 (Box 5)
      - Lavoisier Documents File: Drawer #1, Bundle #2 of 4 (Box 5)
        Biblioteque de l'Institut; Biblioteque Nationale; American Philosophical Society; letters from, to, about, and unrelated to Lavoisier; Ellner - offenback coll.
      - Lavoisier Documents File: Drawer #1, Bundle #3 of 4 (Box 5)
        Lavoisier's major works, Minor separate works
      - Lavoisier Documents File: Drawer #1, Bundle #4 of 4 (Box 5)
        Biblioteque Mun. d'Orlians
      - Lavoisier Documents File: Miscellaneous Bundle (Box 5)
        Separated out and worked on by C. Perrin, problems in "Ask Sam" data base
      - Lavoisier Document File: Drawer #2, Bundle #1 of 6 (Box 5)
        Archives Nationale
      - Lavoisier Document File: Drawer #2, Bundle #2 of 6 (Box 5)
      - Lavoisier Document File: Drawer #2, Bundle #3 of 6 (Box 5)
      - Lavoisier Document File: Drawer #2, Bundle #4 of 6 (Box 5)
      - Lavoisier Document File: Drawer #2, Bundle #5 of 6 (Box 5)
      - Lavoisier Document File: Drawer #2, Bundle #6 of 6 (Box 5)
        Clement-Farranol
  - Research materials relating to Lavoisier Bibliography
    - Bibliography Template/Code (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Keysort Classification Code for Lavoisier Documents (with list of repositories) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Lavoisier Project (Box 6, Folder 3)
      APS grant
    - Members of Academy of Sciences (c. 1785) (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Election of Associés etiangeis
    - Calendar Concordances (Box 6, Folder 5)
      I. Tableau de Condordance des Calendueís Gregonéus et Republicain; II. Perpetual Calendar [Including Year Letters 1582-1800]
    - Guide to "Encyclopédie Méthodique" (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Lavoisier: Venel & Rouelle (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Methodoligical & Conceptual "Roots of Lavoisier's Work"
    - Lavoisier's Chemistry in the New World (Box 6, Folder 8)
      A Study in the Transmission of European Science
    - Early Ideas on Chemical Role of Air (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Origins of Lavoisier's Program (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Imponderable Fluids (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Detonation of Nitre (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Contrasts in Style -- Priestley & Lavoisier (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Mme Lavoisier (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Lavoisier's Proto-Traité (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Encyclopédie/Nouveau Dictionnaire (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Source Material [18 Reference Works]; 1) Excerpts from "Encyclopedie", 2) Excerpts from "Neuveau Dictionnaire françois"
    - Schufle on Bergman to Scheele (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Lavoisier & Chem. Affinity (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Chemistry as Peer of Physics (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Napolean & Newton (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous papers: bibliography, errata, Dexter Award article (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Letter from Lavoisier To Franklin [2 February 1790] & Franklin Letter to Mme Lavoisier [23 October 1788] (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Black and Lavoisier (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Lavoisier-Laplace (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Definition of Chemistry (timeline) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Culleir and Affinity (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Georse Martine & Boerhaave (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Introductiontis Memoir on Hear (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Work in Geneva (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - York University Folders (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Lists of Other Collections (Box 6, Folder 31)
      Microfilms des Papiers Lavoisier déposés à l'Académie des Sciences reproduisant des documents des Archives de Chabrol; Inventory of Fonds Chabrol; Récentes acquisitions Lavoisier
    - Lavoisier Letters: "Catalogue Préliminaire", R. Fric, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      Arch Lnt Hert Sci 2(1949) 619-670 (copy)
    - Inventory of Fonds Chabrol (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence de Lavoisier: Lis of letters sur the profeded volume for 1787, 1787 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence de Lavoisier: Index of Proper Names; Chronological List (Fascicles I-III) (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Sources for the Chemical Revolution (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Documents to Order from the Academy (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Documents on Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 38)
      Lists, photocopies from Histoire de L'académie des Sciences and La Correspondance du Duc de la Rochefoucauld D'Enville et de Georges Louis le Sage
    - Lavoisier Letters at Archives Nationales, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      confiscated during revolution and publ. by D. Mckie; Notes and Records 7(1949) 1-41
    - Chabral (Carton Grimaux) Letters (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence and copies of Documents (Box 6, Folder 41)
      Package from Musée Lecoq to Carl Perrin
    - Notes on Chemists (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: Guyton de Morveau and Tingy, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Notes: Letters and articles to photocopy (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Bibl. Clermont-Ferrand Coll. de Chayelles MS 338; Letter: Landriani to Mme Lavoisier (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Titres Honorifiques de Tingry (2 letters), 1786/1978 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Landriani Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Magellan Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Ms. Tingry (no 34 à 38, no 4 f 47), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Lettres à J. Senebier, 1783-1784/1978 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      Court de Gébelin, La Blancherie (4 letters en entier), Mongez le jenne; MS suppl. 1039
    - Correspondence de Senelier et Spallangani, 1790 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Prospectus d'un cours (gratuit) de chymie théorique et expérimentale (copies) (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Lettres à Senebier, 1776-1791/1978 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      Priestly (5 letters), Rozier (1 letter), Scopoli (1 letter), Viano (3 letters)
    - P.F. Tingry, Cours de Chymie, 1788/1978 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Papiers Gosse, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Envelope for Photocopies from Genève Bibliothèque publique, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Bibliographies/Lists of Other Collections (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Senebier/Geneva Group (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Letters to Senebier (1 & 2) (Box 6, Folder 59-60)
- Series III. Research Notebooks (Cataloged Separately)
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 1: Notebooks 1-5
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 2: Notebooks 6-11
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 3: Notebooks 12-20
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 4: Notebooks 21-28
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 5: Notebooks 29-34
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 6: Notebooks 35-44
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 6: Notebooks 45-49
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 8: Notebooks 50-58
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 9: Notebooks 59-64
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 10: Notebooks 65-70
  - 4710 Bd. Ms. 11: Notebooks 71-74